Prints and Printing Photograph Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Prints and Printing Photograph Collection
1900-2005
VRC 8
Yale University Arts Library
20.6
49 boxes
Collection of mounted black and white and color reproductions of Asian, European, American, and other original and reproductive prints, as well as examples of printing and related processes. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Conditions Governing Access
These materials are stored offsite at the Library Shelving Facility. For access to the materials, please make a request at the Art & Architecture Library.
Arrangement
Organized generally into Asian and other categories. Arranged by country and sub-arranged by individual artist sections preceded by anonymous groupings arranged chronologically.
Scope and Contents
Collection of mounted black and white and color reproductions of Asian, European, American, and other original and reproductive prints, as well as examples of printing and related processes. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Prints; Printing; Photographs; Reproductions
- Printing. (Box 1)
  - Lettering., 8 (Box 1)
  - Printed Book., 111 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous works., 10 (Box 1)
    - Britain., 11 (Box 1)
    - France., 15 (Box 1)
    - Germany., 19 (Box 1)
    - Holland., 28 (Box 2)
    - Italy., 12 (Box 2)
    - Spain., 7 (Box 2)
    - Switzerland., 8 (Box 2)
    - United States., 1 (Box 2)
- Prints. (Box 3)
  Scope and Contents
  Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings.
  - Asian., 340 (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous works., 1 (Box 3)
    - China., 16 (Box 3)
      - Unknown artists., 7 (Box 3)
      - Known artists., 9 (Box 3)
        - Chang Yang-Hsi, XX C., 1 (Box 3)
        - Ch'en Yen-Ch'iao, XX C., 1 (Box 3)
        - K'ang-Hsi, 1662-1723 (Ch'ing)., 2 (Box 3)
        - Li Ch'un, XX C., 1 (Box 3)
        - Shih Lu, XX C., 1 (Box 3)
        - Zoa Wou-Ki, 1920-., 3 (Box 3)
    - Japan., 323 (Box 3)
      - Unknown artists., 9 (Box 3)
      - Known artists., 314 (Box 3)
        - Miscellaneous artists., 52 (Box 3)
          - Bumpo, Kawamura, 1779-1821., 2 (Box 3)
          - Buncho, Tani, 1763-1840., 1 (Box 3)
          - Chikanobu, Hashimoto, XIX C., 1 (Box 3)
          - Choki, Eishosai, active 1772-1795., 2 (Box 3)
          - Eisen, Keisai, 1790-1848., 2 (Box 3)
          - Eishi, Hosoda (Chobunsai), 1756-1829., 3 (Box 3)
          - Eisho, Hosada, active 1780-1800., 1 (Box 3)
            Same as entry above?
          - Gakutei, ?., 1 (Box 3)
          - Hokkei, ?., 1 (Box 3)
          - Hokuei, Shunkosai, 1829-1837., 1 (Box 3)
          - Hokuju, Shotei, active 1789-1818., 1 (Box 3)
          - Inagaki, Tomoo, XX C?., 2 (Box 3)
          - Jihei, Sugimura, active XVII-XVIII C., 1 (Box 3)
          - Kangetsu, Shitomi, 1747-1797., 2 (Box 3)
          - Kiosai, Kawanabe, ?., 1 (Box 3)
          - Kiyomitsu, Torii, 1735-1785., 1 (Box 3)
          - Kiyomitsu, Torii II, 1787-1868., 1 (Box 3)
          - Kiyonobu, Torii, 1664-1729., 1 (Box 3)
          - Kiyotada, Torii, active 1710-1740., 1 (Box 3)
          - Kunimasa, Utigawa, 1773-1810., 1 (Box 3)
          - Kwaigetsudo, active 1707-1714., 1 (Box 3)
          - Masayoshi, Kitao, 1764-1824., 2 (Box 3)
          - Munakata, ?., 1 (Box 3)
          - Shigemasa, Kitao, 1739-1819., 1 (Box 3)
          - Shun'ei, Katsukawa, 1762-1819., 1 (Box 3)
          - Shunko, Katsukawa, 1743-1812., 3 (Box 3)
          - Shigemasa, Kitao, 1739-1819., 1 (Box 3)
          - Shunman, Kubo, 1757-1820., 5 (Box 3)
          - Torii, Genjin, XX C., 1 (Box 3)
          - Toshinobu, Okumura, active c.1717-1750., 2 (Box 3)
          - Toyohiro, Utagawa, 1773-1828., 2 (Box 3)
          - Utagawa, Toyokuni, 1796-1825., 1 (Box 3)
          - Yeiri, active 1789-1800., 1 (Box 3)
          - Yoshitora, Utagawa, XIX C., 1 (Box 3)
          - Yoshitoshi, 1839-1892., 2 (Box 3)
        - Individual artists., 262 (Box 4)
          - Buncho, Ippitsusai, active c.1765-1792., 4 (Box 4)
          - Harunobu, Suzuki, 1724-1770., 25 (Box 4)
          - Hiroshige, Ando, 1797-1858., 39 (Box 4)
          - Hokusai, Katsushika, 1760-1849., 25 (Box 4)
          - Kiyohiro, Torii, active 1751-1765., 3 (Box 5)
          - Kiyomasu, Torii, active c.1696-1716., 4 (Box 5)
          - Kiyonaga, Torii, 1752-1815., 12 (Box 5)
          - Kiyonobu, Torii, 1702-1752., 7 (Box 5)
          - Koryusai, Isoda, active c.1764-1788., 9 (Box 5)
          - Kunisada, Gototei, 1786-1864., 5 (Box 5)
          - Kuniyoshi, Igusa, 1797-1861., 5 (Box 5)
          - Masanobu, Kitao, 1761-1816., 6 (Box 5)
          - Masanobu, Okumura, 1686-1746., 10 (Box 5)
          - Moronobu, Hishikawa, 1616-1694., 3 (Box 5)
          - Sharaku, Toshusai, active 1794-1795., 37 (Box 5-, Box 6)
          - Shunsho, Katsukawa, 1726-1793., 15 (Box 6)
          - Toyokuni, Utagawa, 1769-1825., 16 (Box 6)
          - Toyonobu, Ishikawa, 1711-1785., 5 (Box 6)
          - Utamaro, Kitagawa, 1754-1806., 27 (Box 6)
          - Yeishi, Chobunsai, 1756-1829., 5 (Box 7)
  - Non-Asian., 3275 (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous countries., 3 (Box 7)
      - Poland., 2 (Box 7)
        - Derkovitz, Jozsef, XX C., 1 (Box 7)
        - Marcoussis, Louis, 1882-1941., 1 (Box 7)
      - Rumania., 1 (Box 7)
        - Brauner, Victor, 1903-1966., 1 (Box 7)
    - Austria., 18 (Box 7)
      - Unknown artists., 1 (Box 7)
      - Miscellaneous artists., 5 (Box 7)
        - Danhauser, Josef, 1805-1845., 1 (Box 7)
        - Hundertwasser, Friedensreich, 1928-., 1 (Box 7)
        - Lobisser, Switbert, 1878-., 2 (Box 7)
        - Thulden, T. A., active 1635., 1 (Box 7)
      - Individual artists., 12 (Box 7)
        - Kokoschka, Oskar, 1886-1980., 2 (Box 7)
        - Mucha, Alphonse Marie, 1860-1939., 8 (Box 7)
        - Schiele, Egon, 1890-1918., 2 (Box 7)
    - Belgium., 15 (Box 7)
      - Miscellaneous artists., 4 (Box 7)
        - Alechinsky, Pierre, 1927-., 1 (Box 7)
        - Cox, Jan, 1920-., 1 (Box 7)
        - De Bruycker, Jules, 1870-1945., 1 (Box 7)
        - Gilsoul, Victor O., 1867-., 1 (Box 7)
        - Masereel, Frans, 1889-1972., 1 (Box 7)
      - Individual artists., 10 (Box 7)
        - Ensor, James, 1860-1949., 10 (Box 7)
    - Britain., 390 (Box 7)
      Includes two folders of miscellaneous prints.
      - Unknown artists., 5 (Box 7)
      - Known artists., 385 (Box 7)
        - Miscellaneous artists., 88 (Box 7)
          - Agar, John, active 1795-1835., 1 (Box 7)
          - Austin, Robert, 1895-., 1 (Box 7)
          - Bagdatopolous, W. S., ?., 1 (Box 7)
          - Baxter, George, 1804-1866., 2 (Box 7)
          - Beardsley, Aubrey, 1872-1898., 2 (Box 7)
          - Beggarstaff, (W. Nicholson and J. Pryde), XIX C., 1 (Box 7)
            See also: William Nicholson, below.
          - Blackmore, active 1791., 1 (Box 7)
          - Briscoe, Arthur J. T., 1873-1943., 2 (Box 7)
          - Brockhurst, Gerald Leslie, 1890-1978., 2 (Box 7)
          - Buck, A., ?., 1 (Box 7)
          - Buck, Nathaniel and Samuel, active 1749., 2 (Box 7)
          - Burke, Thomas, 1749-1815., 1 (Box 7)
          - Burne-Jones, Edward, 1833-1898., 3 (Box 7)
          - Calvert, Edward, 1799-1883., 1 (Box 7)
          - Cohen, Harold, 1928-., 1 (Box 7)
          - Cruikshank, George, 1792-1878., 1 (Box 7)
          - Dighton, Robert, 1752-1814., 1 (Box 7)
          - Earlom, Richard, 1743-1822., 1 (Box 7)
          - Faithorne, W., XVII C., 1 (Box 7)
          - Gabain, Ethel, 1882-., 2 (Box 7)
          - Gainsborough, Thomas, 1727-1788., 1 (Box 7)
          - Gardiner, W. N., 1766-1814., 1 (Box 7)
          - Gibbings, Robert, 1889-., 2 (Box 7)
          - Griggs, Frederick, 1876-1938., 3 (Box 7)
          - Grozer, Joseph, 1755-1799., 2 (Box 7)
          - Hamilton, Richard, 1922-., 1 (Box 7)
          - Hayter, Stanley W., 1901-., 2 (Box 7)
          - Hellyer, Thomas, active 1800., 1 (Box 7)
          - Holloway, T., 1748-1827., 1 (Box 7)
          - Hoyland, John, XX C., 1 (Box 7)
          - Hunt, Charles, 1803-1877., 1 (Box 7)
          - Hunt, William Holman, 1827-1910., 1 (Box 7)
          - Jones, Allen, 1937-., 1 (Box 7)
          - Jones, John, 1740-1797., 2 (Box 7)
          - Kapp, Helen, XX C., 1 (Box 7)
          - Kitaj, Ronald B., 1932-., 1 (Box 7)
          - Knight, Laura, 1877-1970., 1 (Box 7)
          - Koehler, George Frederic, XVIII C., 1 (Box 7)
          - MacMurdo, Arthur, 1851-1926., 1 (Box 7)
          - Minton, John, 1917-1957., 1 (Box 7)
          - Monk, William, 1889-., 1 (Box 7)
          - Nash, Paul, 1889-1946., 1 (Box 8)
          - Nevinson, C. R. W., 1889-., 2 (Box 8)
          - Newhouse, C. B., active 1820., 1 (Box 8)
          - Nicholson, William, 1872-1949., 1 (Box 8)
          - Osborne, Malcolm, 1880-., 2 (Box 8)
          - Palmer, Samuel, 1805-1881., 3 (Box 8)
          - Payne, John, 1607-1647., 1 (Box 8)
          - Pellegrini, Carlo, 1839-1889., 1 (Box 8)
            Also known as "Ape."
          - Platt, John E., 1886-., 1 (Box 8)
          - Pollard, James, 1792-1867., 1 (Box 8)
          - Reading, Burnet, active 1776-1882., 1 (Box 8)
          - Roberts, David, 1796-1864., 2 (Box 8)
          - Rogers, William, XVI C., 1 (Box 8)
            Photo is mounted on small board-- it may be hard to find.
          - Rosenberg, C., XIX C., 1 (Box 8)
          - Rossetti, Dante Gabriel, 1828-1882., 2 (Box 8)
          - Sherwin, William, 1645-1715., 1 (Box 8)
          - Smith, Percy, XX C., 1 (Box 8)
          - Strang, William, 1859-1921., 1 (Box 8)
          - Synge, E. M., 1860-1913., 1 (Box 8)
          - Tenniel, J., 1820-1914., 1 (Box 8)
          - Tilson, Joe, 1928-., 1 (Box 8)
          - Turner, Charles, 1773/4-1857., 1 (Box 8)
          - Wadsworth, Edward, 1889-1949., 1 (Box 8)
          - Ward, Leslie, 1851-1922., 1 (Box 8)
            Also known as "Spy."
          - Webb, Joseph, XX C., 1 (Box 8)
          - Wood, John, XVIII C., 1 (Box 8)
          - Wright and Zeigler, ?., 1 (Box 8)
        - Individual artists, A-Z., 296 (Box 8)
          - Barry, James, 1741-1806., 15 (Box 8)
          - Bewick, Thomas, 1753-1828., 3 (Box 8)
          - Blake, William, 1757-1827., 44 (Box 9)
          - Blampied, Edmund, 1886-., 4 (Box 9)
          - Bone, Muirhead, 1876-., 10 (Box 9)
          - Brangwyn, Frank, 1867-1956., 8 (Box 9)
          - Cameron, David Young, 1856-1945., 19 (Box 10)
          - Egerton, Daniel Thomas, active 1824-1842., 12 (Box 10)
          - Fitton, Hedley, 1858-1929., 3 (Box 10)
          - Gill, Eric, 1882-1940., 4 (Box 10)
          - Haden, Francis Seymour, 1818-1910., 6 (Box 10)
          - Hankey, W. Lee, 1869-1952., 5 (Box 10)
          - Hockney, David, 1937-., 7 (Box 10)
          - Hogarth, William, 1697-1764., 34 (Box 10-, Box 11)
          - Jackson, John Baptist, 1701-1780., 3 (Box 11)
          - Leech, John, 1817-1864., 2 (Box 11)
          - Leighton, Clare, 1900-., 3 (Box 11)
          - McBey, James, 1883-1959., 25 (Box 11)
          - Millais, John Everett, 1829-1876., 2 (Box 11)
          - Moore, Henry, 1898-1986., 3 (Box 11)
          - Nutter, William, 1754-1802., 3 (Box 11)
          - Rowlandson, Thomas, 1756-1827., 10 (Box 11)
          - Smith, John Raphael, 1752-1812., 3 (Box 12)
          - Sutherland, Graham, 1903-., 3 (Box 12)
          - Turner, J. M. W., 1775-1851., 44 (Box 12)
          - Ward, William, 1766-1826., 18 (Box 12)
          - Westall, Richard, 1765-1836., 3 (Box 13)
    - Czechoslovakia., 6 (Box 13)
      - Known artists., 6 (Box 13)
        - Miscellaneous artists., 6 (Box 13)
          - Sandzen, Birger, XIX-XX C., 2 (Box 13)
          - Svabinsky, Max, 1873-., 4 (Box 13)
    - Denmark., 5 (Box 13)
      - Known artists., 5 (Box 13)
        - Miscellaneous artists., 5 (Box 13)
          - Gauguin, Paul Rene, 1911-., 1 (Box 13)
          - Lorch, Michael, 1527-1583/6., 1 (Box 13)
          - Nielsen, Palle, 1920-., 1 (Box 13)
          - Vasegaard, Sigurd, XX C., 1 (Box 13)
          - Zorn, Asger, 1914-., 1 (Box 13)
    - Flanders., 54 (Box 13)
      - Unknown artists., 4 (Box 13)
        - XV Century., 2 (Box 13)
        - XVI to XVII Century., 2 (Box 13)
      - Known artists., 50 (Box 13)
        - Miscellaneous artists, A-Z., 14 (Box 13)
          - Anthoniszoon, Cornelius, c.1499-1553., 1 (Box 13)
          - Bellaert, Jacob, XV C., 1 (Box 13)
          - Bosch, Heironymus, c.1462-1516., 1 (Box 13)
          - Coecke, Pieter van Aelst, 1502-1550., 1 (Box 13)
          - Crabbe, Frans Espleghem, 1494-1553., 1 (Box 13)
          - De Bry, Theodore, 1528-1598., 2 (Box 13)
          - Galle, Theodor, 1571-1633., 1 (Box 13)
          - Gheyn, Jacob de, 1565-1629., 1 (Box 13)
          - Hameel, Alart du, c.1300., 1 (Box 13)
          - Straet, Jan van der, 1503-1605., 1 (Box 13)
          - Veldener, Jan, 1474-1477., 1 (Box 13)
          - Vorsterman, Lucas, 1595-1675., 1 (Box 13)
          - Wierix, Jan, 1549-1615., 1 (Box 13)
        - Individual artists., 36 (Box 13)
          - Brueghel, Pieter, 1525-1569., 14 (Box 13)
          - Jegher, Christoffel, 1596-1652/3., 4 (Box 13)
          - Rubens, Peter Paul, 1577-1640., 2 (Box 13)
          - Van Dyke, Anthony, 1599-1641., 16 (Box 13)
    - France., 695 (Box 14)
      - Unknown artists., 18 (Box 14)
        - XIV to XVI Century., 9 (Box 14)
        - XVII to XVIII Century., 4 (Box 14)
        - XIX to XX Century., 5 (Box 14)
      - Known artists., 677 (Box 14)
        - Miscellaneous artists, A-Z., 96 (Box 14)
          - Adams, Henri-George, 1904-., 1 (Box 14)
          - Alix, Pierre Michel, 1762-1817., 2 (Box 14)
          - Appian, Jacques, 1818-1898., 2 (Box 14)
          - Arnollet, Jacques, c.1500., 1 (Box 14)
          - Arnoult, Nicolas, XVII C., 1 (Box 14)
          - Bachelier, ?., 1 (Box 14)
          - Beatrizet, Nicholas, 1507-1570., 1 (Box 14)
          - Bellange, Jacques, c.1594-1638., 2 (Box 14)
          - Benedictus, Edouard, XIX-XX C., 1 (Box 14)
          - Bernardus, S., active 1515., 1 (Box 14)
          - Berthon, Paul, 1872-1909., 1 (Box 14)
          - Bonheur, Rosa, 1822-1899., 1 (Box 14)
          - Boucher, Francois, 1703-1770., 3 (Box 14)
          - Boudin, Eugene, 1824-1896., 1 (Box 14)
          - Bouisset, Firmin, XIX-XX C., 1 (Box 14)
          - Bouquet, c.1800., 1 (Box 14)
          - Carriere, Eugene, 1849-1906., 1 (Box 14)
          - Charlet, Nicolas-Toussaint, 1792-1845., 2 (Box 14)
          - Clement, Charles, 1889-1972., 2 (Box 14)
          - Colin, M. Paul-Emile, XX C., 1 (Box 14)
          - Cross, Henri-Edmond, 1856-1910., 1 (Box 14)
          - De Feure, Georges, XIX-XX C., 2 (Box 14)
          - Delaunay, Robert, 1885-1941., 1 (Box 14)
          - Delaune, Etienne, 1818-1883., 1 (Box 14)
          - Diaz de la Pena, Narcisse, 1807-1876., 1 (Box 14)
          - Diderot, Denis, 1713-1785., 3 (Box 14)
          - Dubuffet, Jean, 1901-1985., 4 (Box 14)
          - Erte, 1892-1990., 1 (Box 14)
          - Fragonard, Jean-Honore, 1732-1806., 1 (Box 14)
          - Gayon, Pierre, c.1495., 1 (Box 14)
          - Girardet, Paul, 1821-1893., 1 (Box 14)
          - Goerg, Edouard, XX C., 1 (Box 14)
          - Gobo, Georges, ?., 1 (Box 14)
          - Grasset, Eugene, 1845-1917., 1 (Box 14)
          - Helleu, Paul Cesar, 1855-1927., 1 (Box 14)
          - Huet, Paul, 1803-1869., 1 (Box 14)
          - Isabey, Jean Baptiste, 1767-1855., 2 (Box 14)
          - Jacque, Charles, 1813-1894., 1 (Box 14)
          - Jory, Geoffroy, active 1545., 1 (Box 14)
          - Kiffer, Charles, 1902-., 1 (Box 14)
          - Labourer, J., 1877-., 1 (Box 14)
          - Lalanne, Maxime, 1827-1886., 1 (Box 14)
          - Laurencin, Marie, 1885-., 1 (Box 14)
          - Laurens, Henri, 1885-1954., 1 (Box 14)
          - Le Mire, Noel, 1724-1801., 1 (Box 14)
          - Maillard, c.1495., 1 (Box 15)
          - Marchand, Gui, active 1494., 1 (Box 15)
          - Mathurin, Meheut, 1882-1958., 1 (Box 15)
          - Metzmacher, 1863-1889., 1 (Box 15)
          - Molas, Nicolas de, XX C., 1 (Box 15)
          - Morin, ean, c.1600-1650., 2 (Box 15)
          - Papillon, Jean Michel, 1639-1710., 1 (Box 15)
          - Pigouchet, active 1498., 1 (Box 15)
          - Pisarro, Lucien, 1863-1944., 2 (Box 15)
          - Prud'Hon, Pierre Paul, 1758-1823., 2 (Box 15)
          - Raffaelli, Jean Francois, 1850-1924., 1 (Box 15)
          - Raffet, Auguste, 1804-1860., 1 (Box 15)
          - Rajon, Paul A., 1843-1888., 1 (Box 15)
          - Ribot, Theodule, 1823-1891., 2 (Box 15)
          - Riviere, Henri, 1864-1951., 1 (Box 15)
          - Saint Aubin, Gabriel de, 1724-1788., 1 (Box 15)
          - Saint-Aubin, Augustin de, 1736-1807., 1 (Box 15)
          - Schuppen, ierre Louis van, 1623/7-1702., 1 (Box 15)
          - Simon, Francois, XIX-XX C., 1 (Box 15)
          - Singier, Gustave, 1909-., 1 (Box 15)
          - Steinlen, Alexandre Theophile, 1859-1923., 1 (Box 15)
          - Valadon, Suzanne, XIX-XX C., 1 (Box 15)
          - Varin, Raoul, XIX C., 1 (Box 15)
          - Vasarely, Victor, 1908-., 1 (Box 15)
          - Verard, Antoine, c.1500., 3 (Box 15)
          - Vernet, Carle, XIX C., 1 (Box 15)
          - Vernet, Horace, 1789-1863., 1 (Box 15)
          - Verpilleux, Emile A., XIX-XX C., 1 (Box 15)
          - Villon, Jacques, 1875-1963., 1 (Box 15)
          - Watteau, J. A., 1684-1721., 1 (Box 15)
          - Wille, Jean Georges, 1717-1807., 1 (Box 15)
        - Individual artists, A-Z., 581 (Box 15)
          - Arp, Jean, 1887-1966., 3 (Box 15)
          - Bonnard, Pierre, 1867-1947., 12 (Box 15)
          - Braque, Georges, 1882-1963., 19 (Box 15)
          - Bresdin, Rodolphe, 1825-1885., 3 (Box 15)
          - Buhot, Felix, 1847-1898., 8 (Box 15)
          - Callot, Jacques, 1592-1635., 11 (Box 16)
          - Cezanne, Paul, 1839-1906., 4 (Box 16)
          - Corot, Jean Baptiste Camille, 1796-1875., 4 (Box 16)
          - Daumier, Honore, 1808-1879., 74 (Box 16-, Box 17)
          - Debucourt, Louis Philibert, 1755-1832., 5 (Box 17)
          - Decaris, Albert, 1901-., 4 (Box 17)
          - Degas, Edgar, 1834-1917., 29 (Box 17)
          - Delacroix, Eugene, 1798-1863., 11 (Box 17)
          - Derain, Andre, 1880-1934., 3 (Box 17)
          - Dore, Paul Gustave, 1832-1883., 17 (Box 17)
          - Drevet, Pierre, 1663-1738., 5 (Box 17)
          - Duchamp, Marcel, 1887-1968., 1 (Box 18)
          - Dufy, Raoul, 1877-1953., 3 (Box 18)
          - Duvet, Jean, 1485-1561., 4 (Box 18)
          - Edelinck, Gerard, 1640-1707., 3 (Box 18)
          - Fantin-Latour, Henri, 1836-1904., 13 (Box 18)
          - Forain, Jean Louis, 1852-1931., 10 (Box 18)
          - Fragonard, Jean Honore, 1732-1816., 2 (Box 18)
          - Gauguin, Paul, 1848-1903., 18 (Box 18)
          - Gericault, Theodore, 1791-1824., 14 (Box 18)
          - Gill, Andre, 1840-1885., 4 (Box 18)
          - Gillot, Claude, 1673-1722., 5 (Box 18)
          - Ingres, J. A. D., 1780-1867., 2 (Box 18)
          - Janinet, Francois, 1753-1813., 9 (Box 19)
          - Jonas, Lucien, 1880-., 3 (Box 19)
          - Leger, Fernand, 1881-1955., 5 (Box 19)
          - Legros, Alphonse, 1837-1911., 13 (Box 19)
          - Lepere, Auguste, 1844-1918., 5 (Box 19)
          - Lorrain, Claude, 1600-1982., 10 (Box 19)
          - Maillol, Aristide, 1861-1944., 5 (Box 19)
          - Manet, Edouard, 1832-1883., 10 (Box 19)
          - Masson, Andre, 1896-1987., 4 (Box 19)
          - Masson, Antoine, 1636-1700., 4 (Box 19)
          - Matisse, Henri, 1869-1954., 16 (Box 20)
          - Mellan, Claude, 1598-1688., 2 (Box 20)
          - Meryon, Charles, 1821-1868., 17 (Box 20)
          - Millet, Jean Francois, 1814-1875., 11 (Box 20)
          - Moreau le Jeune, J. M., 1741- after 1814., 4 (Box 20)
          - Nicolle, Emile, 1830-1894., 3 (Box 20)
          - Nanteuil, Robert, 1623/30-1678., 24 (Box 20)
          - Pillement, Jean, 1727-1808., 3 (Box 21)
          - Pissarro, Camille, 1830-1903., 4 (Box 21)
          - Redon, Odilon, 1840-1916., 14 (Box 21)
          - Renoir, Pierre Auguste, 1841-1919., 8 (Box 21)
          - Rouault, Georges, 1871-1958., 13 (Box 21)
          - Segonzac, Andre Dunoyer de, 1885-1974., 3 (Box 21)
          - Signac, Paul, 1863-1935., 3 (Box 21)
          - Tissot, James, 1836-1902., 4 (Box 21)
          - Toulouse-Lautrec, Henri de, 1864-1901., 31 (Box 21)
          - Villon, Jacques, 1875-1963., 47 (Box 22)
          - Vlaminck, Maurice de, 1876-1958., 3 (Box 22)
          - Vuillard, Edouard, 1868-1940., 12 (Box 22)
    - Germany., 602 (Box 22)
      Includes two folders of miscellaneous clippings.
      - Unknown artists., 63 (Box 22)
        - Miscellaneous works., 3 (Box 20)
        - XV Century., 49 (Box 22-, Box 23)
        - XVI Century., 11 (Box 23)
      - Known artists., 539 (Box 23)
        - Miscellaneous artists, A-Z., 109 (Box 23)
          - Altdorfer, Erhard, active c.1512-1561., 2 (Box 23)
          - Amman, Jost, 1539-1591., 2 (Box 23)
          - Baselitz, Georg, 1938-., 1 (Box 23)
          - Bauer, Rudolf, 1889-., 2 (Box 23)
          - Baumeister, Will, 1889-1955., 1 (Box 23)
          - Beck, Leonard, c.1480-1542., 1 (Box 23)
          - Beham, Hans Sebald, 1500-1550., 2 (Box 23)
          - Bellmer, Hans, 1902-1975., 2 (Box 23)
          - Biel, G., active 1509., 1 (Box 23)
          - Bommel, Wolfgang Hieronymus von, c.1700., 4 (Box 23)
          - Buisinck, Rudolph, 1590-1630., 1 (Box 23)
          - Burghers, Michael, c.1640-c.1723., 1 (Box 23)
          - Businck, Ludwig, 1590-1669., 1 (Box 23)
          - Corinth, Lovis, 1858-1925., 1 (Box 23)
          - Deutsch, H. von, 1525-1572., 1 (Box 23)
          - Drewes, Werner, 1899-., 2 (Box 23)
          - Dreyer, Friedrich Adolph, 1780-1850., 1 (Box 23)
          - Felixmuller, Conard, 1897-1977., 1 (Box 23)
          - Fischer-Lamberg, Otto, 1870-., 1 (Box 23)
          - Flach, Martin, active 1500., 1 (Box 23)
          - Ghotan, Bartholomaeus, active1492., 1 (Box 24)
          - Goltzius, Hubertus, 1525-1583., 2 (Box 24)
            Also known as Hubert and Hubrecht.
          - Grimm, Wilhelm, 1904-., 1 (Box 24)
          - Han, Ulrich, active 1473., 1 (Box 24)
          - Hann, Trier, 1915-., 1 (Box 24)
          - Hollar, Wenzel, 1607-1677., 4 (Box 24)
          - Hofer, Karl, 1878-1955., 1 (Box 24)
          - Hopfer, Daniel, active 1493-1536., 2 (Box 24)
          - Hopfer, Hieronymous, active 1520-1550., 2 (Box 24)
          - Jawlensky, Alexej ven, 1864-1942., 1 (Box 24)
          - Kaldenbach, Martin, 1470-1518., 1 (Box 24)
          - Kilians, Wolfgang, active 1623., 1 (Box 24)
          - Klinger, Max, 1857-1920., 1 (Box 24)
          - Knoblochtzer, Heinrich, c.1483., 1 (Box 24)
          - Lehmbruck, Wilhelm, 1881-1919., 1 (Box 24)
          - Leibl, Wilhelm, 1844-1900., 1 (Box 24)
          - Liebermann, Max, 1847-1935., 1 (Box 24)
          - Loy, Erasmus, active 1520-1570., 1 (Box 24)
          - Macke, August, 1887-1914., 1 (Box 24)
          - Manuel, Nicklaus, c.1484-1530., 2 (Box 24)
          - Marcks, Gerhard, 1889-1981., 1 (Box 24)
          - Master B. M. of the Upper Rhine School, XV C., 1 (Box 24)
          - Master B. R., active 1480-1490., 1 (Box 24)
          - Master F. V. B., active 1455-1480., 1 (Box 24)
          - Master B x 8 (Bartel Schon?), active c.1470., 1 (Box 24)
          - Master I. A. M. Zwolle, active c.1485., 1 (Box 24)
          - Master I. E., or Schongauer, M., XV C., 1 (Box 24)
          - Master L. C. Z., XV C., 1 (Box 24)
          - Master L. C. Z., XV C., 1 (Box 24)
          - Master of the Aachen Madonna, XV C., 1 (Box 24)
          - Master of the Amsterdam Cabinet, active 1470-1510., 1 (Box 24)
          - Meckenem, Grahel van, -1503., 1 (Box 24)